The dance of Los Mirlos.
Sabor! Sabor!
Hands in the air, hands in the air, hands in the air.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,hey, hey, hey! All right!
Let's go, let's go!
Los Mirlos. Los Mirlos, inspired by the majesty of the Amazon.
By the diversity of its cultures and the richness of its traditions.
We pay tribute to the Amazon rainforest.
To its riches, its mysteries, myths and legends that are the spirit and heartbeat of the jungle.
So that you feel the magic, the charm and the sound of the jungle.
Los Mirlos.
"The Cumbia of the Jaguar." Let's go.
Clap your hands. Clap your hands. Hands up, up, up, up, up.
That's it. Ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay,ay, ay, ay!
Dance, dance, dance. Dance. Dance
Cumbia. Cumbia. Cumbia. Cumbia. Cumbia.
Amazonian.
From the Peruvian Amazon.
To the United States and the world.
Let's go.
Hands in the air. Up, up, up, up.
Wepa!
The Cumbia of the Jaguar. Nice.
Keep going, keep going, keep going, keep going, keep going.
Cumbia. Cumbia. Cumbia.
Of the Jaguar.
Amazonian cumbia is a celebration, but it is also the voice of the earth.
Listen closely to the guitars, that is how the jungle roars when it cried for help.
We dedicate this song to all our Indigenous brothers and sisters who defend the lungs of the world.
Even with their own lives.
Lament.
Lament in the jungle.
Go over there. Let's go. Let's go, let's go, let's go.
The jungle weeps in sorrow over the departure of my brothers.
We remember them and sing to them with this lament.
Lament in the jungle.
All right.
Keep it going, keep it going.
The jungle weeps in sorrow over the departure of my brothers.
We remember them and sing to them with this lament,
lament in the jungle.
Thank you very much.
Los Mirlos is a musical group.
Sharing music and culture from the Peruvian Amazon for more than 52 years.
My origins, my beloved homeland Moyobamba, the heart of the Amazon.
Very pleased, very happy.
We continue enjoying these beautiful songs.
Let's go with Los Mirlos. Play it!
A night of love. Let's go!
Keep it up. Keep it up. Keep on going.
When the jungle makes a sound, Los Mirlos sing.
Night falls. Night falls.
Night falls.
Cumbia, cumbia, cumbia.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
A night of cumbia.
With you, my love.
The night.
That's it!
We Peruvians have been blessed with three beautiful regions in Peru.
As Peruvians, we truly feel very happy, very pleased.
To have three regions: the coastal region on the shores of the Pacific Ocean,
the Andean region, where Cusco, Machu Picchu, and other beautiful cities are.
And the Amazon region, my homeland, Moyobamba, and the entire Peruvian Amazon.
Truly, we are very happy.
Long live Peru! Live!
Long live the Amazon! Live!
Long live the world! Live!
Congratulations!
And now, everyone dance "La Pandilla"!
For all the towns of the Peruvian Amazon.
Moyobamba, Pucallpa, Iquitos, Tingo María, Yurimaguas, Tarapoto.
Puerto Maldonado and the entire Peruvian Amazon.
Let's go. Ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay, ay!
Ay! Ay! Ay!
Doña Guillermina, let's dance. Doña Guillermina. Let's dance.
Grab your partner.
Let's jump.
Grab your partners. Let's jump.
The group dances, I dance too.
The group dances, I'll dance too.
Come on, come on, everyone. Everyone dance.
Come on, come on, everyone. Everyone have fun.
Ay! Ay! Ay! Ay!
Doña Guillermina, let's dance.
Grab your partners, let's dance.
Grab your partners, let's jump.
The group dances, I dance too.
Come on, come on, everyone. Everyone dance.
Come on, come on, everyone. Everyone enjoy.
Come on, come on, come on! That's it.
Stomp, stomp, stomp, stomp, stomp.
Well, thank you very much for being here. To all the ladies, to all the gentlemen, truly.
We Los Mirlos feel very happy to be here at this grand event.